Guide to the Newton Camp Farr papers, [ca. 1933-1967]
Farr, Newton Camp papers, [ca. 1933-1967]
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Newton Camp Farr papers, [ca. 1933-1967]
2848
Newton Camp Farr, 1887-1967.
5 cubic ft.
Publications and correspondence.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes publications of the Urban Land Institute, International Real Estate Federation, and the Chicago Department of City Planning. Also, correspondence of the Urban Land Institute, the National Association of Real Estate Boards, the San Diego Chamber of Commerce, and the Harvard Law Review.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
In 1912, Farr joined the firm of Farr, Chinnock & Sampson, Inc., Chicago's oldest real estate firm, founded by his father in 1872. He also advised many cities on redevelopment and renewal as a member and former president of the Urban Land Institute. Member, International Fraternity of Lambda Alpha, Ely Chapter.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes publications of the Urban Land Institute, International Real Estate Federation, and the Chicago Department of City Planning. Also, correspondence of the Urban Land Institute, the National Association of Real Estate Boards, the San Diego Chamber of Commerce, and the Harvard Law Review.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Farr, Newton Camp, 1887-1967.; Chicago (Ill.). Dept. of Planning.; International Real Estate Federation.; National Association of Real Estate Boards.; San Diego Chamber of Commerce.; Urban Land Institute.; Lambda Alpha International. Ely Chapter.
Titles:
Harvard Law Review.
Subjects:
City planning.; City planners.
Places:
Chicago (Ill.); Illinois.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Publications, Reports and Printed Matter (Box 1)
  - Department of City Planning, Chicago, publications (Box 1)
  - Urban Land Institute Panel Study to Boise, Idaho (Box 1)
  - International Real Estate Federation, publication (Box 1)
  - Committee for Economic Development, programs (Box 1)
  - Urban Land Institute, publications - technical bulletins (Box 1)
  - Urban Land Institute, technical bulletins, c. 1955-1967 (Box 2)
  - Urban Land Institute, newsletters, 1943-1966 (Box 2)
  - Misc. publications (Box 2)
  - Chicago Plan Commission publication, 1942 (Box 3)
  - Omaha City Planning Commission reports, 3 parts, 1945 (Box 3)
  - "A Limited Way Plan for Greater Chicago Traffic Area", October 1933 (Box 3)
  - The Comprehensive Plan of Chicago, Department of Development and Planning, 118 pp., December 1966 (Box 3)
  - Illinois Resources, 185 pp., 2 copies, November 1944 (Box 3)
  - Printed matter (ca. 1/3 of the contents of the box) (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute, Technical Bulletins (old) and other printed material (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute, Research Monographs, ca. 1959-1965 (Box 5)
  - Misc. planning reports pertaining mostly to Chicago, Illinois (Box 5)
- Correspondence files
  - "The Class of 1909 of Cornell" binder of correspondence; circular letters, mostly pertaining to Cornell Fund, 1943-1951 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence regarding the Urban Land Institute (Box 2)
  - Chamber of Commerce, San Diego Conference, March 4, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute, Sagamore, N.Y., October 5, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute, Philadelphia, January 11, 1951 (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute, Columbia, Missouri, December 5-6, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute, Minneapolis Chamber of Commerce, Downtown Council, August 14, 1956 (Box 4)
  - Urban Land NAREB, Cedar Rapids, Iowa, May 9, 1955; 10 (Reel 4)
  - Urban Land Institute--Battle Creek, panel meeting and previous, February 21, 1956 (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute, Boise, Idaho, panel, September 17-22, 1965 (Box 4)
  - NAREB--Hawaiian conference, November 1953 (Box 4)
  - NAREB--Educational, Gainesville, Florida, February 16-26, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute, panel--Wichita, Kansa, October 20, 1955 (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute--Syracuse, panel meeting (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute--Sagamore, Syracuse University, October 5-9, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute, Walter Schmidt Memorial (Box 4)
  - Urban Land--NAREB, Vancouver, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute--Mexico City, panel meeting, April 1965 (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute, St. Louis panel, April 5-6, 1955 and October 11-16, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute, Indianapolis panel, September 23-27, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Harvard Law Review, interview on urban renewal (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute, Dallas, Texas, January 29, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute, Columbus, Ohio, panel, June 10, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute, Cleveland, panel meeting (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Urban Land Institute, 1964-1965 (Box 4)